

Gaurav Nikam

Senior Systems Engineer

Experienced professional with 2.8 years of work history as software development and support engineer in the IT industry, delivering web applications and services employing agile methodologies to ensure the quality and timely delivery of applications to customers.

🔀 gauravnikam06@gmail.com

Pune, India

linkedin.com/in/gaurav-nikam-b445941bb

7887740330

April 03, 1998

github.com/gauravnikam01

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Systems Engineer Infosys

09/2020 - Present

Pune

Achievements/Tasks

- INSTA Award for showcasing technical excellence for project deliverables (Nov 22, Feb 23).
- RISE Gracias recognition for team coordination and Quick fixes provided in warranty period post deliverables (Jan 23).
- o Certificate of Excellence award during Pune client visit (March 23).

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Customer Create and Maintain Portal (04/2021 - 07/2022)

- O Client: Westpac Group, Australia
- Understanding the requirement from technical perspective. Involved in development of all functionalities and Unit testing with all possible scenarios.
- Responsible for fixing all the defects at different phases of testing and also maintaining code quality checks via sonar cube and preparing documents for same.
- Responsible for successful implementation of KYC Checks for Savings and Transaction Products for Consumer and Business Customers.

Service Online and Customer Establishment (07/2022 - Present)

- o Client: Westpac Group, Australia
- Involved in technical requirement design analysis, Unit testing, Implementation and fixing defects during different stages of testing cycles.
- Providing the demos to business stakeholders during different phases of build.
- Working on release management activities to prepare package production ready including security scans and confirming final changes.
- Responsible for successful delivery for several Payment related projects such as restriction of personal contact details to OFI without customer consent, enabling customers to raise service request against any Direct Debit payments, etc.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of EngineeringSKN College of Engineering, Pune University

08/2016 - 08/2020

Branch

Computer Engineering

HSC and SSC Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya, Nashik

06/2009 - 06/2016

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages : Java, JavaScript, SQL, HTML and CSS

Enterprise Frameworks and Libraries : Spring, Spring Boot, Rest APIs, RESTful Webservices, React JS, Tailwind CSS and Redux

Data Structure and Algorithms

Database: Oracle

Unit Testing Frameworks : JUnit, Mockito

IDE: IntelliJ Idea, Eclipse, Visual Studio Code

Version Control Software: Bit Bucket

Developer Tool: Postman, Swagger

Code Quality: SonarQube

Other Tools: JIRA, Confluence, Beyond Compare WinSCP, Git, GitHub

CERTIFICATES

Infosys Certified Full Stack Developer
Infosys Global Agile Developer

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Marathi

Full Professional Proficiency

HIndi

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Football

Cricket

Capital Market

Reading Fiction

F1